# SUKHWINDER SINGH

**८**+91−94170077405 **?** Noida, India

**■** sukhwindernagpal@yahoo.in **■** singhsukhwinder13 **○** singhhsukh **☆** singhhsukh.github.io

Software Professional with experience of more than 7 years in software development. Highly Skilled in Back end development using both Java and Python, handling Big Data using PySpark ,Databases using Postgres, Snowflake and Elastic search and developing APIs using Python Frameworks- Django and Flask. A Very good communicator and have good experience of working directly with the client in Agile Environment. Graduated in Information Technology from National Institute of Technology Jalandhar.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages & Frameworks: Python[PySpark], Django[DRF], FastAPI, Java[maven]

Cloud & DevOps: AWS, AZURE, OCI, K8s, Docker, Jenkins Databases: PostgreSQL, Snowflake, ElasticSearch

Misc.: Git, Databricks, Redis, Kafka

#### **EXPERIENCE**

SDE-2 Jun 2022 - Present Innovaccer Noida, India

- Spearheaded the development and deployment of Kafka-based service for a **healthcare clients**, facilitating data interoperability for various **EHRs**.
- Participated in development of an **ODR System** to read data from various EHR's FHIR APIs and provide uniform response to calling application. Currently, Developing a **Pub-sub event Bus** to serve multiple applications with minimum information provided.
- Designed and implemented a **FHIR** data transformation tool to facilitate patient data access via APIs in compliance with FHIR standards. Successfully deployed the tool across multiple U.S.-based customer environments using **AWS** and **Azure**.

## Python Developer (IC3)

Oracle

March 2019 - January 2022 Hyderabad, India

- Co-designed the **architecture** of Fusion Automation, an automation framework, using **Python with Django Rest Framework**. Played a key role in integrating **cloud** components(AWS, AZURE) to drive automation and innovation.
- Developed **ML modules** within the Fusion Automation framework to enhance failure analysis and predictive capabilities using **Python and machine learning techniques**. Focused on improving diagnostic accuracy and predictive insights.

## **Associate Consultant**

July 2017- March 2019

Capgemini

Hyderabad, India

- Part of a team responsible for delivering customized software solutions, focusing on backend development with Java and SQL.
- Engaged in software development lifecycle activities, including requirement analysis, coding, testing, and client demos.

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Business Administration(Part-time), Information Technology

2021-2023

2013 - 2017

LPU DE

Jalandhar, India

Bachelor of Technology(Full-time), Information Technology

Jalandhar, India

National Institute of Technology

#### **AWARDS**

- Recipient of Leading by Example Award in November 2024 at Innovaccer.
- Recipient of Outstanding Solution Award in July 2024 at Innovaccer.
- Recipient of the **Best Product award(Team)**, only awarded to Handful of Product teams in Oracle.

# INTERESTS

# Reading

Classic Novels, Crime and Thriller Novels, Punjabi & Urdu Poetry

## **Sports**

Football, Cricket, Badminton

The only player to captain teams in both football and cricket Innovaccer internal tournaments and win them in the same year.